# 大家好 不知道怎麼回事 我們家的公鼠又不夠啦
Hi everyone. I don't know why but we are running out of male rats again.
# 我看一下兄弟家有沒有 向他借一點
Let me see if we can borrow some from our brother.
# 他的棚子在這裡
The shed is right there.
# 這是我兄弟 帶我看一下這個竹鼠
This is my brother. He is taking me to see his bamboo rats.
# 他家這裡養了好多哦
He has a lot.
# 這些就是配種的
These are for breeding.
# 這麼胖
So fat!
# 這個 下面有鋼網的話
With the, with the steel net,
# 這衛生就很好搞
it's much easier to clean the cells.
# 幾乎都不用搞
You don't even need to clean it.
# 它自己會漏下去
The waste simply falls from the net.
# 從下面掃掉就行了
and you only need to clean the floor.
# 如果全 全都[SIC](鋼)網了也行
You can make it only, only with the net,
# 那裡加了一塊瓷板的話就怕它那個太冷了
but a porcelain board over there is because, because the cell is too cold otherwise.
# 加了塊瓷板可以保暖一下哦
It can keep the cell warm with the board,
# 因為有個窩
since it can make the lair.
# 到時候後期的話 我們做池子的話也要搞成這樣子
Later, when we make the new cells, we shall make this kind of cells.
# 搞衛生的話就不用那麼累 掃都不用掃了
Doing the cleaning will be much less tiring. We don't even need to brush the cells.
# 你看這個 這幾個都是公的哦
You see these rats? They are all male.
# 頭上的毛都不見了
They don't have hair on the head.
# 肯定會有一隻
There must be one,
# 有一隻
one,
# 吃毛的
eating the hair
# 它們的毛都吃完了
Their hair is all eaten away.
# 全都是
All are...
# 這連毛都不見了
All the hair is gone.
# 很結實哦 它的肉
It's very firm, its flesh.
# 好大條
Very big.
# 這都兩斤多啊這個
It is over a kilogram.
# 兩斤半啊
Over a kilogram.
# 好重啊
Very heavy.
# 哇 這個公的 你看
Wa! This male rate is, see?
# 好肥呀
is very fat.
# 這樣 就像小胖
It's like, like Small Fatty
# 呃 這樣公的很漂亮的哦
Ah! A male rat like this one is very pretty.
# 將近四斤多
It's almost 2kg.
# 而且它又不胖
And in fact it is not fat.
# 也不是很胖 你看 它身材特別長
It's not very fat. See? It is very long.
# 很適合作種 很適合作種鼠的這種
This is very suitable, very suitable for breeding.
# 去不去我家
Do you want to go home with me?
# 帶你去
I'll take you to,
# 帶 帶你去
take, take you to
# 我家那個竹鼠棚裡面 很好玩的哦
the sheds at my place. There is so much fin.
# 不願意去
It doesn't want to.
# 老是在掙扎
It doesn't stop struggling.
# 我又嚇到它了
I scared it.
# 這個也是很胖的哦 這個哦
This is also very fat, this one.
# 也不是胖 它很長條
In fact this is not fact. It is very long.
# 毛色發亮
The hair is shiny.
# 那麼聽話 這個
So gentle and nice, this is.
# 它肯定不認識我
Surely it doesn't know me.
# 認識我之後它肯定是掙扎
It would be struggling should it know me well.
# 拼命的在掙扎 你看
Struggling with all its might. See?
# 它以為我跟它玩
It thinks that I were simply playing with it.
# 去不去我家 去不去我家
Do you want to go home with me? Do you?
# 很好玩的
There is a lot of fun!
# 去不去
Are you going?
# 聽不懂人話
It doesn't understand human language.
# 放回去了
Put it back.
# 你看 兄弟家的公鼠 全部都是一公一母 正在配種
See? The male rats at my brother's place are all coupled with a female. They are breeding.
# 借不了啊 等它們配 等那個母的
I can't borrow. I'll come again when they fin..., when the female
# 懷 懷孕了我再來借
get, get pregnant.
# 好聽話呀
So nice!